Mohammed Rafiq Junior Software Developer

Email: amirrafiq24@gmail.com Mobile: +44 7521557791

Address: Keighley Github: Amir2341

Personal Profile

A Northcoders graduate who has previous experience within administration and customer service. I decided to start my developer journey, and change careers, in order to have the opportunity to face new challenges, learn new skills and be able to create applications which can improve people's day to day lives. Northcoders is an industry led bootcamp, which has taught me a variety of technical skills which can be translated into working efficiently in Junior roles.

Technical Skills

Languages: JavaScript, Typescript

Front End: React, React Native, HTML, CSS3, CSS Frameworks

Back End: Express, SQL, Firebase, Node.js

Testing: Jest

Experience

Northcoders Coding Bootcamp Student

Leeds

June 2022 - September 2022

- Attended a 13 week coding bootcamp where I learnt full stack software development taught using an industry led curriculum.
- Throughout the bootcamp was taught best practices such as Agile, Test Driven Development, pair programming and git version control.

Front-end Project - NC - News website - a reddit style news website which was built using React.js and designed using CSS3

Technologies used:

React.js - CSS3

https://amir-nc-news.netlify.app//https://github.com/Amir2341/NC-News-FE

Back-end Project - NC - News server - a backend server API with endpoints that are used to retrieve data for the NC News front end project, It was built using Express.js, Node.js and the data was inputted and queried using PostgreSQL. It was built with test driven development using Jest.

Technologies used:

Node.js - Express.js - PSQL - test driven development - Jest https://nc-news20.herokuapp.com/ / https://github.com/Amir2341/NC-news-project

Final Project - Full Stack - Scan N Pan - a mobile recipe app which lets you use your leftover ingredients and match them with recipes. React Native was used to build the app and Firebase was used to create the backend api to store the recipes and was also used to add authentication functionality to the app Technologies used:

React Native – Agile Development – Firebase - CSS3 - Expo https://github.com/Amir2341/scan-n-pan

Ant Marketing Call Handler

Sheffield January 2021- May 2022

- Increased customer satisfaction by resolving issues
- Worked with customers to understand needs and provide excellent service
- Communicating with patients effectively using my time management and problem-solving skills, to efficiently input the sensitive Information into the systems portal.
- Participating and leading multiple NHS campaigns has allowed me to adapt to any
 working scenario, as I can successfully think on my feet and present my ideas to a
 group of peers.
- Administration-based work such as responding to emails, setting up meetings and answering phone calls.
- Handling sensitive information for the NHS and adhering to the Caldicott principles.

Education

Bradford University

Chemistry Degree September 2017 - September 2020

Bingley Grammar School

A-Levels September 2015 - June 2017 Biology-B Chemistry- C Mathematics-C

Bingley Grammar School

GCSEs
September 2009- July 2015
10 GCSE'S A*-C including Maths and English

References

References available upon request